Ladies and gentlemen,
1 2 3.
>> Ready when you are. 3 2 1 go.
>> Dude, you all right?
>> I'm good.
>> Steady.
Damn it. Okay, so OpenAI just released
Sora 2 which is the latest version of
the video generation model and hands
down this is probably the best video
generation model that we have seen to
date. It can not only generate realistic
looking images which follow physics but
it can also generate sound effects
dialogue very similar to V3. And they
also released a new social media app
called Sora by OpenAI.
Think of this as Tik Tok for AI
generated videos. More on that later in
the video. So in this video, I'm going
to show you some outputs from this new
model. Now it's pretty amazing, but it's
far from perfect. It also has some weird
failure cases, but I think overall this
is probably the best video generation
model that is out there. So, here's the
official blog post. They say that it's
more physically accurate, realistic, and
controllable than prior systems. That
seems to be actually the case. Now, it
also can generate synchronized dialogue
and sound effects. We're going to look
at some few examples later in the video.
According to OpenAI, this might be the
GPT 3.5 moment for video. Sora 2 can do
things that are exceptionally difficult.
So, for example, it can do Olympic
gymnastic routines, back flips on the
pedal board, right? So, here are some
examples. Now, for this particular clip,
watch right here. So you can actually
see that the girl at the end was
expecting the ball to come to her. The
ball didn't come to her, but you can see
that the hand movement shows that the
ball is in her hands. So that's a
failure case. Now I'm going to turn on
the sound for some of these so that you
actually see how synchronized the audio
is with the video.
>> That's cold.
Folks keep saying you can't ride a
horse. It's riding a horse. [music]
Guess nobody told these two.
Steadiest pair I've ever had under me.
>> MY GOT IT.
>> UP. UP.
>> COVER MIDDLE.
>> OUTSIDE. OUTSIDE.
>> I'm on it.
>> SET.
>> GO.
CLOSE. Nice swing.
>> Good job, y'all.
And the interesting thing is that it's
able to generate dialogues and also
commentary which is pretty incredible
because just by looking at this scene
it's able to generate realistic
commentary from the audience. Really
incredible stuff that we are seeing.
It's going to be extremely hard to
differentiate between reality and AI
generated stuff. So in the blog post
they say that prior video models are
over optimistic. They will morph objects
and deform realities to successfully
execute
upon a text prompt. For example, if a
basketball player misses a shot, the
ball may spontaneously teleport to the
hoop. Right? According to Openai Sora 2,
if basketball player misses a shot, it
will rebound off the backboard. Right?
So, it definitely follows physics laws
much more realistically. And in the live
stream I talked about creating world
model where the model actually learns
about realistic world and physics. And
those things show up in the results that
they have shared. So here are a couple
of more outputs. IT'S
>> COLLAPSING.
>> NO, WE PUSHED TO THE SUMMIT. NOW WE HAVE
A WIN.
knowledge is not a destination. It's a
companion for the road.
>> So you can see from very simple prompts
it can generate dialogues. And the
interesting thing was especially with
this video that the sound effects that
it generates are very relevant to the
video that is being generated which is
incredible. We saw native audio within
videos with VO3. Then a week or so ago
we saw this with one 2.5 preview but
Sora actually takes it to a whole new
level.
So apart from the video generation
capabilities, they also introduced a new
app called Soda where you can introduce
yourself into these AI generated videos.
And you can actually have multiple
people. So for example, here is an open
AI employee.
>> The forest is perfect for hiding. I
think I just found something. Look at
the size of this print. Wait, did you
see that? Something's moving over there.
That's got to be him. I'm going after
it.
>> Hey there, traveler.
>> This is wild. Turns out I can actually
fly. Watch. Ready? Look. Totally off the
ground. LET'S GO OUTSIDE. The view up
here is insane. I can just drift around
like still figuring out the landing, but
it's the best feeling ever.
>> Come on. Some cases, it's really hard to
see even the artifacts that are usually
noticeable in AI videos, especially the
character consistency in these images is
pretty incredible. You can see that from
one shot to another, it keeps the
character or person consistent. And this
is driven by an image of the person. So
pretty incredible stuff. Okay, let's
talk about availability. So you can
download the Sora iOS app today. It's
going to be only available to US and
Canada starting today, but they have an
invite system, so not everybody is going
to get access. Sora 2 will initially be
available for free with generous limits
to start so people can freely explore
its capabilities and then they're going
to make it available to chat GPT pro
users. Again we don't know when exactly
this is going to come out because they
say that it's a invite only system at
the moment. Second thing is they are
going to be releasing sort 2 API as
well. I would suspect that we're
probably going to see a tweet from
OpenAI saying that the demand is more
than they expected. So there might be
some delay in terms of rollout, but
we'll have to see that. So if I go to
sora.com, here's what I'm seeing. Meet
the new Sora. Turn your ideas into
videos with improved motion and sound
instantly. And now I need to enter the
invite code. So if anybody has an invite
and would like to share it, please send
it my way. I will be very thankful.
Okay. So they really want to create a
social experience around Sora 2. So here
they talk about the deployment of Sora 2
on the road to general purpose
simulation and AI system that can
function in the physical world. We think
people have a lot of fun with the models
we're building along the way. Right?
They talk about this idea of upload
yourself which brings us to this Sora
app. The feature they're calling it
cameo. So you can uh create AI videos of
yourself or your friends based on their
permissions. Now I haven't seen anything
about the duration of the uh video. So
for Cameo, you actually need need to
record a short one-time audio and video
so that the app can verify and also
capture your likeness. Now for something
like this, there are going to be a lot
of privacy related issues. Also, I
personally don't know how to feel about
yet another social media app that is
driven entirely by AI. It can
definitely, but I think we already have
enough social media. Okay, so here
they're saying we're giving users the
tools and optionality to be in control
of what they see on the feed. So they
will have a recommener system that you
can instruct through natural language
which is a very interesting option
unlike Tik Tok or YouTube shorts. You
might be able to drive the type of
things that you want to see in your
feed. So initially this will heavily be
biased towards people you follow or
interact with and prioritize videos that
model things you are most likely to use
as an inspiration for your own
creations. It's a social media app so
they want people to interact with their
friends and hence they're creating this
invoice based app only. Then they talk
about protecting the wellness well-being
of teens. So, they're going to have
limits on the number of generations that
they can see in their feed per day.
Also, for adults, they're going to have
reminders to take some time off to cool
down, which I think is a good thing.
Again, I am not really in favor of these
social media apps where you spend a lot
of time doom scrolling. But then they
talk about monetization. So they say a
lot of problems with other apps stem
from the monetization model
incentivizing decisions that are at odds
with user well-being. Transparently, our
only current plan is to eventually give
users the option to pay some amount to
generate an extra video if there is too
much demand relative to available
compute. As the app evolves, we will
openly communicate any changes in our
approach here while continuing to keep
user well-being as our main goal.
Now, I don't know if they will also give
users the ability to monetize their
content. That might be yet another
revenue stream for OpenAI, but we'll
have to see. Personally, I'm pretty
impressed by the innovations that they
have made in terms of the coherence and
the ability of the model to follow
physics, which is pretty incredible. And
as I said, it's far from perfect. So you
might see some failure cases, but this
is just the second iteration. Especially
like if you look at this video, you can
actually see there are some deformities
around the hand, how the person is
grabbing onto the tool, right? But this
is just the second iteration, right? I
think for most people who are not
looking specifically for these
deformities, it's going to be pretty
hard to figure out. They're looking at
AI generated content. Now, OpenAI dev
day is next week and I'm going to be
there for the dev day. They have
released quite a few things just before
the dev day. So, it's going to be
incredible to see what exactly they have
in store for dev day. I will be
reporting from there. Anyways, I hope
you found this video useful. Thanks for
watching and as always, see you in the
next one.